Vivian Nwokonko

No 36 Isikwuato Street, Imo, Nigeria | +2347039152816 | @mail | @linkedin | @github

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Versatile developer with a Master's in Biochemistry, distinguished for collaborative skills and a track record of independently delivering impactful results. Ample experience in full-stack development, delivering well-documented, tested, and operable code. Efficient in collaborating and communicating new ideas and opinions.

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Front end Developer | Aptech Computer Education
Front end Developer | Her TechTrail
Best Graduating Student, | MS
3rd Best Graduating Student | BS

February 2023 December 2021 May 2018 June 2014

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: Bootstrap, Webflow, Owlcarousel, Django

DevOps and API Tools: Git

Soft Skills: Problem solving, Communication skills, Critical thinking, Interpersonal relationship

Others: Microsoft Office Suite

EXPERIENCE

Full-stack Developer, Trainee | Aptech Computer, Imo, Nigeria

February 2023 - Present

- Developed responsive, user-friendly web pages which met brand consistency using appropriate frameworks, tools and languages.
- Consistently ensured that our clients websites where maintained and improved over time.
- Designed client-side and server-side architecture.

Front end Developer | *Freelancer*

January 2022 – January 2023

- Collaborated with senior developers to meet target deadlines of various websites projects.
- Designed, developed and implemented software applications for various websites using vast technologies.
- Carried out proper website testing, user testing and troubleshooting before live deployment.
- Assisted back end developers with coding and troubleshooting.

Front end Developer, Apprenticeship | Her TechTrail

October 2021 - December 2021

- Gained basic knowledge on how to design and create scalable web applications
- Acquired in depth understanding of the entire web development process (design, development and deployment).

EDUCATION

University of Port Harcourt, Nigeria University of Port Harcourt, Nigeria MS in Environmental Biochemistry | GPA: 4.45 BS in Biochemistry | GPA: 4.42 January 2016 – May 2018 December 2009 – June 2014

PROJECTS

E commerce website | *Django, HTML, CSS, Java script, Bootstrap*

February 2024

- Designed, developed and deployed an online cake store.
- The online store met clients standard and there was a progressive growth in sales due to the accessibility of the website.

E commerce website | HTML, CSS, Java script, Django

October 2023

- Developed an online car accessories store alongside with senior developers.
- Despite the tight deadline and short notice, we where able to meet target and client's expectations.

Portfolio website | Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

Dec 2021

- Designed and developed my portfolio website while undergoing my apprenticeship.
- The website was user friendly, responsive and got good remarks from my tutors